Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 7: Volumes, 1745-1945; 147 Volumes
  - Nathan Sellers Memorandum books and diaries, 1773-1829, 4.0 Volume(s); Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    - Memorandum book, 1773 (Volume 93)
      Previously housed as B P31.37a
    - Memorandum book, 1774 (Volume 94)
      Previously housed as B P31.37b
    - Memorandum book, 1776 (?) (Volume 95)
      Previously housed as B P31.37c
    - Nathan Sellers diary, 1817-1829, June, 1817-Oct., 1829 (Volume 96)
      Previously housed as B P31.37d
    - Typescript of diary, 1776 (Volume 97)
      Previously housed as B P31.37e
  - Nathan Sellers account book, 1774-1815., 2.0 Volume(s) 2 volumes, 340 p.; The volumes include accounts of the firm of Nathan and David Sellers, with records of sales to the Continental Congress, Pennsylvania Committee of Safety, Thomas Fitzsimons, Thomas Leiper, John Penn, Stephen Sayre, Edward Shippen, Anthony Wayne, and others; also sketches of watermarks designed for special customers.; 2 volumes, 340 p.; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    - Account book, 1780-1808, Oct. 4, 1780-1808 (Volume 98)
      Previously housed as B P31.38a
    - Account book (Volume 99)
      Previously housed as B P31.38b
  - Nathan Sellers surveying notebooks, 1775-1784, 4.0 Volume(s); The volumes consist of of notes on surveys, 1777-1779; survey of the West Chester road; survey of the State House Yard after 1785, with drafts of letters to Zeba Pyle, 1820-1821.; 4 volumes.; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    - Surveying notebook, 1777, Aug. 15, 1777-July 25, 1777 (Volume 100)
      Previously housed as B P31.39a
    - Surveying notebook, undated (Volume 101)
      Notebook showing one mile per page, Delaware and Chester Counties.
      Previously housed as B P31.39b
    - Surveying notebook, 1820-1821 (Volume 102)
      Previously housed as B P31.39c
    - Surveying notebook, 1784 (Volume 103)
      Contains notes on survey of the road to Reading, PA.
      Previously housed as B P31.39d
  - Notes kept as a member of the Philadelphia Common Council., 1805-1812; 1.0 Volume(s) 1 volume, 70 p.; The volume includes a record of expenditures for cleaning, paving and repaving streets, for the town watch, for the care of wells and pumps for water, etc. Previously housed as B P31.40; 1 volume, 70 p.; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830 (Volume 104)
  - Nathan Sellers receipt book, 1813, 1819-1829., Bulk, 1819-1829; 1813-1829; 1.0 Volume(s) 1 volume, 40 p.; 1 volume, 40 p.; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830 (Volume 105)
    Contains lists and description of lots for sale.
    Previously housed as B P31.41
  - Notes of financial transactions, 1814-1844., 1.0 Volume(s) 1 volume, 75 p.; The volume includes investments in mortgage, stocks, loans, etc. with records of payments. Previously housed as B P31.42; 1 volume, 75 p.; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830 (Volume 106)
  - N. & D. Sellers (Firm) letterbook, 1821-1830, Jan. 11, 1821-Jan. 31, 1830; N. & D. Sellers (Firm) (Volume 107)
    The firm of N. and D. Sellers was engaged in wire working industry and in the manufacture of wool cards and paper molds. After the death of David Sellers in 1813 and the retirement of Nathan Sellers 1817, the business was run by Coleman, son of Nathan, and Samuel and James, sons of David Sellers. In 1828 N. and D. Sellers dissolved with the retirement of Coleman Sellers.
    This volume contains business correspondence of the firm, relating to the sale and shipment of wire and wire products. Correspondents include John Haviland and George Shryock.
    Previously housed as B P31.43
  - Nathan and Coleman Sellers order book, 1834-1836, 2.0 Volume(s); Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    The firm of N. & D. Sellers was engaged in wire working industry and in the manufacture of wool cards and paper molds. After the death of David Sellers in 1813 and the retirement of Nathan Sellers in 1817, the business was run by Coleman, son of Nathan, and Samuel and James, sons of David Sellers. In 1828 N. & D. Sellers dissolved with the retirement of Coleman Sellers.
    Orders for paper molds, with descriptions, and for machine work of different kinds. Customers include William Duane, Thomas Gilpin, Adam Ramage, and John Shryock.
    - Order book, 1835-1836 (Volume 108)
      Previously housed as B P31.44a
    - Order book, 1836, 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 109)
      Previously housed as B P31.44b
  - Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers account books,1834-1845, Sept. 10, 1834-1845; Sellers, Sophonisba Peale, 1786-1859
    Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers was a daughter of Charles Willson Peale.
    - Account book, 1834-1835, Sept. 10-1834-April 8, 1845 (Volume 110)
      Accounts with her sons, Charles and George Escol Sellers, of sums given her by them.
      Previously housed as B P31.45
    - Account book, 1834-1836 (Volume 111)
      Receipt book, containing receipts for payment of taxes, ground rents, groceries, and interest, as administratrix of the estate of Coleman Sellers.
      Previously housed as B P31.46
    - Account of housekeeping expenses, 1840-1844 (Volume 112)
      Record of expenses while keeping house for her son-in-law Alfred Harrold, including wages, carriage fares, "childrens board," and groceries.
      Previously housed as B P31.47
  - Cornelia Wells Sellers correspondence book, 1856-1909, Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909 (Volume 113)
    Correspondence includes 51 letters from relatives and friends in Cincinnati addressed to Mrs. Sellers after her move to Philadelphia.
    Previously housed as B P31.49
  - Cornelia Wells Sellers diaries,1902-1909, 5.0 Volume(s); Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Five volumes (1902-1904, 1906, 1909), which present a detailed account of the lifestyle of a suburban Philadelphia family of that period.
    - Diary, 1902 (Volume 114)
      Previously housed as B P31.54
    - Diary, 1903 (Volume 115)
    - Diary, 1904 (Volume 116)
    - Diary, 1906 (Volume 117)
      Previously housed as B P31.
    - Diary, 1909 (Volume 118)
  - Sellers family genealogical data, 7773-1827, [n.d.]; 1.0 Volume(s); Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933 (Volume 119)
    This data, collected by Horace Wells Sellers, includes extracts from the diaries of Nathan Sellers and Samuel Sellers and materials from other sources.
    Previously housed as B P31.50g
  - Rembrandt Peale palettes, 1833-1855, Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860 (Volume 120)
    These palettes show colors used in some of Peale's paintings, with notes by Peale labeling the mixture of pigments and what the palette was for (i.e., "retouching" and "finishing"). One note refers to Peale's painting of Washington, 1855. Most are undated.
    Previously housed as B P31.51
  - Pronunciation of the Italian Language, Unidentified (Volume 121)
    Writing exercises and Italian grammar/pronunciation lessons. Probably student work of Rembrandt Peale (?).
    Previously housed as B P31.51a
  - Peale family genealogies, 1.0 Volume(s); Peale, Joseph M. (Volume 122)
    Photocopy of a family genealogy prepared by Joseph M. Peale (1931), with an emphasis on the line of James Peale, brother of Charles Willson Peale.
    Previously housed as B P31.52a
  - Peale family genealogy, Unidentified (Volume 123)
    Volume two contains the line of descent from William Peale of Rutlandshire, through Charles Peale of Maryland, to 1950.
    Previously housed as B P31.52b
  - Samuel Sellers receipt book,1828-1839, 1 volume, ca. 172 p.; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850 (Volume 124)
    This volume contains personal accounts with various members of the Sellers family and others.
    Previously housed as B P31.53
  - Correspondence of C. W. Peale and Thomas Jefferson, 1796-1804; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827 (Volume 125)
    Transcripts of letters of C.W. Peale to Thomas Jefferson between the years 1796 and 1804.
    Previously housed as B P31.c
  - Diary, 1815; 6-1/4x4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785 (Volume 126)
    A.D. 28pof which 11 are blank. Journal of a trip.
  - Letterbook containing copies of outgoing letters., 1832; 22p.; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 127)
  - Journal, 1839-1840; 5x8; Peale, Florida, 1825-1847 (Volume 128)
    A.D.S. 1vol.consisting of 20 leaves. (see Peale papers.)
  - Journal, June 22-July 20, 1848-1849; 8-1/2x7; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905 (Volume 129)
  - Diary, Sept. 14-Aug. 17, 1848-1849; 7-1/2x5; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905 (Volume 130)
    A.D. 45p.
  - Diary, July 16-Aug. 3; Jan. 1-June 14, 1849; 1853-1854; 12-1/2x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827 (Volume 131)
    A.D. 120pp.of which 67 contain writing.
  - Recollection of Coleman Sellers By His Son George Escol Sellers, n. d.; 50p.; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 132)
  - Daybook, Undated; 7-3/4x6; Peale, Lucinda (Volume 133)
    D. 1vol.consisting of 24 leaves, of which 15 contain writing. (see Peale papers.)
  - Notes on Charles Willson Peale, undated; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870 (Volume 134)
  - List of photographs taken in Montrose, and Red Bank, New Jersey, June-Sept, 1884; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885 (Volume 135)
    D. 3 notebooks. Various sizes. (see Peale papers.)
  - Lectures., Undated; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Peale, A. C. (Albert Charles), 1849-1914 (Volume 136)
    A.D.S. 1 volume. Incomplete. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Medical lectures.
  - Life of C. W. Peale, Undated; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827 (Volume 137)
    Also bound together: March 20, 1819 C. W. Peale to Titian R. Peale; and March 26, 1819 Rembrandt to Titian Peale.
  - 3 Houses, Green Street, 1784; Little, John (Volume 138)
    Account book of John Little.
    From typed note attached to volume: "...military barricks were constructied in 1756 by the Provincial Commissioners on a large lot bought by them in the Northern Liberties, between Second and Third Streets, south of Green St. ... After the Revolution the barrick property was used as a tavern and later purchased by the Commissioners of Northern Liberties and converted into Commissioners' Hall. In 1784 the Supreme Executive Council determined to lay out lots for building purposes nd offer them for sale. This book indicated that John Little built three houses on the site. It will be noted that N. & D. Sellers furnished the nails."
  - Receipt book, 1791-1793; Unidentified (Volume 139)
  - Account of Smiths and Nailors Work Received Commencing 19 Jan, 1778, and monies paid, etc. etc., Jan. 19, 1778 - Oct. 1779; Little, John (Volume 140)
    From note on inside front cover: "This book was found in attic of Congress Hall 6th and Chestnut Streets druing restoration of building, 1912-1914."
  - Autobiography, undated; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 141)
    Typed and manuscript draft of autobiography, in three parts.
  - Memoirs, Part 1, undated; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 142)
    Typed manuscript of memoirs.
    Presented by C. C. Sellers
  - Memoirs, Part 2, undated; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 143)
    Memoirs, Part 2 of 2.
  - Index of George Escol Sellers' Memoirs, undated; Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-1980; Sellers, George Escol (Volume 144)
    Prepared by C. C. Sellers in his youth.
  - An Album containing a selction of poetry and prose (with some sketches), ca. 1825; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860 (Volume 145)
    Contains paintings of flowers.
  - Peale Museum Silhouettes, undated; Unidentified (Volume 146)
    ca. 65 silhouetter paper cuts, several identified by name of subject.
  - Silhouette album., 1845; Unidentified (Volume 147)
    28 silhouettes, with registry of names at end of vol. Date is taken from note on inside front cover.
  - Sketches by C. W. Peale and T. R. Peale, Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885 (Box 148)
    The box contains a variety of items which were probably at one point part of a bound sketch book. Of particular note are three drawings by C.W. Peale: "Western Tanager," "Two birds 'drawn for Capt. M. Lewis'" and "Horned toad." All three of these are drawings of specimen brought back from the Lewis and Clark expedition.
    Also included are images of Washington, and an unidentified man.
    Previously cataloged as B P31.15a.
    - Two birds, "drawn for Capt. M. Lewis.", ca. 1806; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
      Sketches of California quail and woodpecker(?).
    - Horned lizard (horned toad), collected by Lewis and Clark., 1806; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
      View of horned toad.